<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-04T23:33:38+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Giving $10</title><subtitle>THE $10 CLUB is a group of compassionate individuals who donate $10 (US) every month to be pooled together and used to fund a poverty alleviation project.</subtitle><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><entry><title type="html">Visakha Society for the Protection and Care of Animals</title><link href="/projects-2012/2012/02/29/project-2012-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Visakha Society for the Protection and Care of Animals" /><published>2012-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2012/2012/02/29/project-2012-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2012/2012/02/29/project-2012-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your February 2012 report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 1996, the Visakha Society for the Protection and Care of Animals (VSPCA) has worked to improve the conditions for animals in India, protecting endangered sea turtles, rescuing cows, and providing housing to dogs, cats, and other animals in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout India, there is a connection between stray dogs and cats and impoverished people living on the streets. Homeless people in India might be emotionally traumatized, mentally disabled, or in other ways infirm. The bond these people develop with animals is strong and often an easier relationship than would be possible with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Pradeep Kumar Nath, VSPCA's Founder and President: &quot;In reality they are seeking each other's company to strike a bond of love and affection after being abandoned by their own society and now are building a relationship of life. ... a life is a life and is not related to physical appearance.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2010, VSPCA began a plan to deliver vegan meals to India's poor humans living on the streets. Called the &quot;Kindness Mobile Restaurant,&quot; roughly eighty people are served weekly in three different areas. A wholesome and nutritious vegan meal (lentils, vegetable curry, fruit and one sachet of drinking water) is hygienically packed in palm leaves and provided by auto-rickshaw to the poorest of the poor three days a week (when other charities in the area are not operating).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Giving $10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, 246 of us joined together to donate $2,460 to the Visakha Society for the Protection and Care of Animals in India to provide 5,000 food packets to homeless people in need serving dozens of people three times a week for an entire year. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nath writes: &quot;Every one of them has a trusted association with a street dog. They give the first morsel of food to the dog that comes at that time to get their first share. Both the poor person and the street dog have both overcome loneliness in having each other as companions.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India has some 1.2 billion people, 30% of whom live in urban areas. 237 million people or one in five are malnourished. Nearly half of India's children are malnourished to the point of being underweight and having their growth stunted. The breadth of the problem is overwhelming. But for about 80 of the poorest of the poor in the country, for the rest of the year, food insecurity will not be a problem thanks to your small sacrifice this month!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><category term="projects-2012" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hôpital Albert Schweitzer Haiti</title><link href="/projects-2012/2012/01/31/project-2012-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hôpital Albert Schweitzer Haiti" /><published>2012-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2012/2012/01/31/project-2012-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2012/2012/01/31/project-2012-1.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your January 2012 report for Giving $10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1956, the mission of Hôpital Albert Schweitzer Haiti (HAS) has been to collaborate with the people of the Artibonite Valley as they strive to improve their health and quality of life. Thanks to HAS, district residents even in the remote mountains can find health care within reach and at an affordable cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address the root causes of diarrhea and malnutrition, and now cholera which emerged in epidemic proportions in Haiti in 2010, HAS has focused on community health and development activities, including drilling wells and providing sanitation, which have allowed many families to have access to clean drinking water and latrines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pont Sondé is a key market and transport hub at the edge of the HAS district. The local economy revolves around transportation, commodity marketing, and rice. Roughly 4,000 people live in the in-district parts of Pont Sondé, with many more in the adjacent parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geologically the area is challenging, with salt deposits in the alluvial sand and gravel underlying much of the area. Potable groundwater sits in a lens on saline water, and in some areas is at risk of contamination by fertilizers used in the many nearby rice fields. Residents must get their water either from shallow wells or from rainwater capture. Thus, this area has a high need for at-home water treatment to ensure that contaminants are removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAS has been building and installing thousands of Biosand filters in the past decade, allowing more than 15,000 people to have access to potable drinking and wash water. The Biosand technology is very practical. Users do not need great skill to use it and necessary maintenance is easy to do, making the Biosand filter very suitable for the rural environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Giving $10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, 225 of us joined together to donate $2,250 to HAS to install nearly 50 new filters in high-need households in the Pont Sondé area in the Artibonite Valley of Haiti. They will undertake spot-testing of water quality to identify particularly high-need households and provide the community with education in potable water, sanitation, and hygiene. A local mason will be contracted to produce, deliver, and install the filters and an HAS mason technician will ensure the quality control of construction and installation. He will also train residents in filter use and maintenance. Recipient families will visited later to make sure each water filter continues to work and receives proper maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water filters stave off dehydration - a leading cause of death among Haitian children under the age of five - as well as gastrointestinal disease. These simple Biosand units filter out up to 95% or more bacteria and virtually 100% of larger organisms, particularly giardia and other cysts which are resistant to chlorine. The end result will be drinking, cooking, and bathing water that meets water quality standards for hundreds of people at risk.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><category term="projects-2012" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends: Welcome to your January 2012 report for Giving $10. Since 1956, the mission of Hôpital Albert Schweitzer Haiti (HAS) has been to collaborate with the people of the Artibonite Valley as they strive to improve their health and quality of life. Thanks to HAS, district residents even in the remote mountains can find health care within reach and at an affordable cost. To address the root causes of diarrhea and malnutrition, and now cholera which emerged in epidemic proportions in Haiti in 2010, HAS has focused on community health and development activities, including drilling wells and providing sanitation, which have allowed many families to have access to clean drinking water and latrines. Pont Sondé is a key market and transport hub at the edge of the HAS district. The local economy revolves around transportation, commodity marketing, and rice. Roughly 4,000 people live in the in-district parts of Pont Sondé, with many more in the adjacent parts. Geologically the area is challenging, with salt deposits in the alluvial sand and gravel underlying much of the area. Potable groundwater sits in a lens on saline water, and in some areas is at risk of contamination by fertilizers used in the many nearby rice fields. Residents must get their water either from shallow wells or from rainwater capture. Thus, this area has a high need for at-home water treatment to ensure that contaminants are removed. HAS has been building and installing thousands of Biosand filters in the past decade, allowing more than 15,000 people to have access to potable drinking and wash water. The Biosand technology is very practical. Users do not need great skill to use it and necessary maintenance is easy to do, making the Biosand filter very suitable for the rural environment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SUUBI Community Development Initiative</title><link href="/projects-2011/2011/12/31/project-2011-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SUUBI Community Development Initiative" /><published>2011-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2011/2011/12/31/project-2011-12</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2011/2011/12/31/project-2011-12.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your December 2011 report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The citizens of Uganda continue to suffer from poverty, locked in the lowest third of ranked nations in the United Nations Development Programme's Human Development Index (161 out of 187). Average life expectancy at birth is 54. Ugandans have to worry about cholera, malaria, and AIDS. AIDS is especially traumatic on families, taking parents away from their children forever. There are estimated to be more than two million orphans in the country today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These children need to rely on some form of health and education services in order to meet their basic needs. And, of course, the government is ill-equipped to fully handle the situation. They often end up living with relatives who have their own children already and are therefore unable to care for their new residents fully. Children often subsist on a single meal each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Butuntumula is a sub-county of the Luwero District in Uganda with approximately 35,000 people. People in the community travel miles to get access to moderately safe drinking water. The elderly, including those suffering from blindness and other debilitations, have to care for children who have lost their parents. Most orphaned children are unable to attend school and some have to work in local markets selling fish while simultaneously looking after their younger siblings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 26 schools in the sub-county serving more than 10,000 students. But orphaned children have an extremely difficult time attending school. Even if enrolled, they need to find a way to acquire food, books, pens, clothes (school uniforms), and other materials necessary to fulfill their education. There is a local community development initiative in Butuntumala run by John Paul Kibalama that aims to assist the orphaned children there with food, provisions, school fees, and educational needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Giving $10&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month, 238 of us joined together to donate $2,380 to the SUUBI Community Development Initiative to help care for 20 orphans in need. Our grant will help the group pay for the school fees for these children, outfit them with school uniforms and casual wear including shoes, provide them with mattresses and bedding and blankets, and make sure they have necessary food to take them through the school terms. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For children who have to literally walk miles to school, who lack proper clothing and adequate, nutritious food, and who have already lost so much in their young lives, your support this month has given them a chance to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><category term="projects-2011" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wells Bring Hope</title><link href="/projects-2011/2011/11/30/project-2011-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wells Bring Hope" /><published>2011-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2011/2011/11/30/project-2011-11</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2011/2011/11/30/project-2011-11.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your November 2011 report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nigeriens have a short life expectancy, 54 years. Forty percent of the population has trachoma, which when left untreated, leads to blindness. Niger also has the highest childbirth rate in the world 7.6 births per woman. One in seven women dies in labor or from complications during pregnancy. Only a third of expectant mothers either deliver at hospital, health post or with the help of a trained midwife at home. As a result, a significant number of women who survive giving birth suffer from complications during labor like obstetric fistula which causes lifelong incontinence and ostracism from their village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Niger, 52% of the entire population and 70% of rural villages lack access to clean water. Women and girls typically walk 4-6 miles per day to find water for their families. Mothers must enlist the help of their daughters for this difficult task. As a result, young girls don't get an education. While the Niger government recognizes the serious need to provide safe water for its people, they can afford to drill only 10% of the 12,000 wells needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lack of access to potable water is the single most important factor for the high mortality rate among children there. One out of four children dies before the age of five, typically from diarrhea or other water-borne diseases. The premature deaths and water-borne diseases can easily be eliminated when a borehole well is drilled in a village. When this happens, public health is dramatically improved and infant mortality drops by 65%. Girls go to school, often for the first time in the history of the village. When girls are educated, they tend to marry later and bear children later, reducing the number of pregnancies and the chances of death in childbirth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wells Bring Hope (WBH) is committed to drilling wells to bring safe water and good sanitation to rural villages of Niger, West Africa one of the poorest countries in the world, according to the 2010 UN Development Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Giving $10&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month, 247 of us donated $2,470 to Wells Bring Hope to help fund the drilling of a well in Niger. This is roughly one-quarter of the well project cost. WBH will campaign to match our grant, and then its partner organization, World Vision, will fund the second half of the project. The well we help fund will serve more than 500 people. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The well will be fully sustainable. Villagers will be educated on how to maintain their well and learn where to get parts for up-keep. The village will also set up a maintenance fund to which everyone in the village contributes, thus ensuring that villagers take responsibility for their well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only the Democratic Republic of the Congo currently ranks below in Niger in human development. If we can help create one water well for one community we will have helped, quite literally, those who are among the poorest of the poor. Surely this is worth $10!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><category term="projects-2011" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kinkizi Rural Development Initiative Trust</title><link href="/projects-2011/2011/10/31/project-2011-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kinkizi Rural Development Initiative Trust" /><published>2011-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2011/2011/10/31/project-2011-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2011/2011/10/31/project-2011-10.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your October 2011 report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kinkizi Rural Development Initiative Trust was started in 2007 by the youth of Bwindi in Mukono parish (Uganda) to unite their efforts in fighting poverty, hunger, illiteracy and malnutrition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their efforts began small with tree nurseries, vegetable gardens, and training community members in how to grow vegetables, including cabbage, spinach, carrots, green peppers, potatoes, tomatoes, onions, and zucchini. The bounty of their harvests was purchased by tourism camps in the area as well as local people for their sustenance. More than 45 people settled on productive farm areas, producing much-needed foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project has grown steadily in the past few years and has trained more than 150 people in vegetable growing, employs 15 members of the community, and has helped 3 people to go back to school to further their studies both in high school and at the university level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By all accounts, the project has been a great success. However, land is difficult to acquire, especially as the Trusts work continues to expand. The more available land, the more opportunities to grow vegetables to benefit the community. But the growers are also making sound business decisions, not just acquiring more land, but utilizing the land to grow the highest value crops, such as mushrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Giving $10&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month, 250 of us donated $2,500 to the Kinkizi Rural Development Initiative Trust to purchase land for a community gardening project. This land will also include the space for construction of a store to sell vegetables, as well as a demonstration garden where budding farmers can learn sustainable gardening skills. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to John Bosco Tusingwire, a representative of the Trust, they are entering into a serious mushroom business. About 30 people have registered to get this special mushroom training at our mushroom gardens. We are determined to feed the world with high quality organic mushrooms. &lt;blockquote&gt;With our mushroom initiative we are expecting every member to be earning at least $150 per month; this is going to be a poverty chain-breaking project.&lt;/blockquote&gt; They are even considering whether there would be export possibilities for their crops to further expand market opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vision of the Trust is simple and clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;To be the leading door to door raw food production and delivery service in south western Uganda, known for quality, efficiency, reliability and customer satisfaction. This, in an effort to create a community that has the potential to use the available resources to be free from poverty, malnutrition and hunger and able to sustain its livelihoods.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, you are a part of the solution for these small-scale, sustainable farmers in Uganda. Their climb out of poverty starts with your support and a mushroom garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Update&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We the members of Kinkizi Rural Development Initiative trust (KIRUDI) are very jovial to communicate to you as a group purposely sending you a vote of thanks for donating to us money to buy a plot of land. It is very hard to see it by mere writing this letter but honestly our innermost hearts are now comfortable and not doubting of where we shall be next time, as it was before we had our own land, in short we are the happiest ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Uganda land is now more precious than Gold especially here in Bwindi, therefore anyone who decides to give you land to farm in Bwindi have given you wealth for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have our own land as a group we are now focusing on permanent plans for sustainable use of our land, we are planning to put up measures that makes sustainable use of our small land for the goodwill of our present community and the future generation. Now that the land is small and strategically positioned we are planning high value crops that will benefit each of us both economically, socially and health wise. Enterprises like nursery bed of vegetables and coffee as well mushroom project are going to be established, the reason being that they occupy small space and give high yield in a short time, also we shall be getting seedling from our plot to go and plant in our home gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We therefore again thank you to help us achieve this great resource which have been our dream for the last 5 years. Thank you for making us get established on our own property. We also send our inmost appreciation to those who contributed as we know this generous heart is not with everybody though they could be having even much to do anything. Please send our innermost thanks to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like as you know we are still trying to establish ourselves we need much more help as you well know that reaching at a self-sustaining stage is not simple especially we the less privileged and marginalized women and men of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have attached a group photo for you to see those who are benefiting or going to benefit from the land and the entire project in general. You may not see us clearly because we took the photos after the meeting late in the evening. It was getting darker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely, &lt;br&gt;Safari Joseph. &lt;br&gt;Chairman for and on the behalf of KIRUDI organization members.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><category term="projects-2011" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">$10 Club Receives E Chievement Award</title><link href="/news/2011/10/18/$10-Club-receives-E-Chievement-Award.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="$10 Club Receives E Chievement Award" /><published>2011-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2011/10/18/$10-Club-receives-E-Chievement-Award</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2011/10/18/$10-Club-receives-E-Chievement-Award.html">&lt;p&gt;Adam Roberts and The $10 Club received the eTown E-Chievement award in a special event in Boulder, CO. The event will air across North America on over 300 stations from October 12th-October 19th, depending on the day and time their individual affiliate stations air the show. Many stations also stream over the web, so you can listen from their websites, anywhere in the world. They also podcast the show. Check eTowns website to find out how and where to tune in: http://www.etown.org/listen.php&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-etown&quot;&gt;About eTown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1991, eTown is a nationally-syndicated radio show heard weekly on over 300 public, community and commercial stations across North America and via podcast. eTown is a nonprofit, 501(c)3 corporation whose mission is to educate, entertain and inspire a diverse audience, through music and conversation, to create a socially responsible and environmentally sustainable world. Every eTown show is taped in front of a live audience, and features performances from many of today’s top musical artists as well as thought-provoking interviews and the presentation of the listener-nominated E-Chievement Award recognizing everyday people who have made a difference in their community or beyond. Founders Nick Forster, of the legendary bluegrass band Hot Rize fame, and his wife, singer/actress Helen Forster host the show. For more information, visit www.etown.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-the-e-chievement-award&quot;&gt;About the E-Chievement Award&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the show’s most popular segments is the E-Chievement Award. Listeners from around the country send in nominations of remarkable individuals who are working hard to make a positive difference in their communities and beyond. From massive river clean-ups to programs that help the homeless, from neighborhood activists to national and international social and environmental organizations, eTown takes pride in celebrating the success stories of ordinary citizens accomplishing extraordinary things. To learn more about the E-Chievement Award, visit www.etown.org.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Adam Roberts and The $10 Club received the eTown E-Chievement award in a special event in Boulder, CO. The event will air across North America on over 300 stations from October 12th-October 19th, depending on the day and time their individual affiliate stations air the show. Many stations also stream over the web, so you can listen from their websites, anywhere in the world. They also podcast the show. Check eTowns website to find out how and where to tune in: http://www.etown.org/listen.php</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Madiana Village</title><link href="/projects-2011/2011/09/30/project-2011-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Madiana Village" /><published>2011-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2011/2011/09/30/project-2011-9</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2011/2011/09/30/project-2011-9.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your September report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madiana is a village of approximately 5,000 people in the small country of The Gambia, located on the northwest coast of Africa. Madiana is about 10 miles from the nearest clinic in a neighboring village, and 50 miles from a larger hospital in the capital Banjul. Donkey carts, bicycles, and for-hire bush taxis provide the only transportation. The dirt roads are nearly impassable during the rainy season, April to November, increasing the remoteness and access to health care. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The village is comprised mostly of subsistence farmers. Women and girls do manual labor, including growing fruits and vegetables for market. Young girls carry the water for irrigating the gardens from a community well, a distance of half a mile. &lt;blockquote&gt;Women and children also harvest mangoes, oranges, and cashews in their seasons, which they take by donkey cart to the market three or more hours away. The men of the village earn limited currency selling charcoal - a labor intensive product that they accomplish by cutting wood with homemade axes. They also sell firewood and some are employed as brick makers. Younger boys pick oranges.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approximately 40% of total out-patient clinic visits in The Gambia are due to malaria. Infant mortality in the region is 84 per 1,000 births, with malaria being the leading cause of death. According to Babba Jammeh, a nurse working with the Village Development Committee in Madiana, approximately 30 deaths per year in the village are attributed to the disease, with pregnant women and children at highest risk. Since malaria mainly occurs during the rainy season, accessing emergency treatment for someone suffering from malaria is a slow process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Madiana Village Development Committee is comprised of one trained nurse, three auxiliary nurses, one staff person, and lay volunteers. Four years ago villagers worked together to build the medical clinic.&quot;The project only got so far before there was just no money to continue. An 18' X 24' cinderblock building has been allocated to house the clinic and is in great need of renovation.&quot; While the clinic would give care to all villagers, its primary focus will be to provide care for pregnant mothers and children and provide discreet education and treatment for HIV/AIDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Giving $10&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month, 250 of us donated $2,500 to Karen Jackson, a registered nurse, who is heading to Madiana to help finish building the clinic and stocking it with supplies. Our grant will be used to purchase corrugated iron sheets, nails, cement, sand, lumber, paint, water pipes, a toilet, beds, chairs, tables, solar panels, batteries and converters. &lt;blockquote&gt;Remaining funds will be used for antibiotics, antifungal creams, vitamins, and antiparasitics. Transportation of materials will be donated and labor will be undertaken by volunteers. Thank you.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gambia is a country that many people will not have heard of, but today you made sure a rural clinic there will be fully operational, serving a population in great need, which would otherwise likely have been ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Update&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Adam and Friends at The $10 Club,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karen Jackson here, your grant recipient for the Health Clinic in Madiana Village, The Gambia West Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned home just two weeks ago - still do not quite have my feet under me. It is difficult to buy a cup of coffee without feeling frivolous. My friend Lucia Robinson and I were in the Madiana Village from February 20th to the 1st of March, then spent a week in the nearby village of Furato, then returned to Madiana until March 12th. During that time I saw and treated approximately 250 patients, with a young girl interpreting who was fluent in three tribal languages - Mandinka, Jola, Fula - and English. Her name is Naffi and she was a god-send. (We have initiated a scholarship to help her finish high school and apply to nursing school).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucia and I had expected to help with the construction, painting and set up of the clinic. Instead, when we arrived, a large village celebration was in progress to open the freshly painted clinic. The workmen proudly showed us the six exam rooms and an office space, two beds, several plastic tables, and long wooden benches for waiting patients to sit on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very next morning we had patients lined up on the porch of the clinic and patients coming to our compound at all hours looking for the &quot;American nurse&quot;. From sun up to sun down we met with mothers and their children. Lucia, an experienced herbalist and health care worker, was taking blood pressures and gathering as much information as she could, while I tended to everything from malaria, hepatitis, burns, parasites, gynecological problems, new born babies and young just-birthed mothers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both had arrived with donations of medical supplies, herbal salves and tinctures, some homeopathic remedies, three solar panels and wiring. Every other day a driver took us into the larger town of Serrakunda to a pharmacy where we restocked with whatever was available - the pharmacies having limited supplies themselves. During our return visit to Madiana, I was able to meet with an Israeli pharmacist who was very helpful in giving me bulk discounts and much needed advise on local diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grant money spread remarkably far and wide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The building is essentially complete, the solar panels were being hooked up and batteries purchased during our final week there. Some income will be generated by the solar panels being utilized to recharge cell phones at a small price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One disappointment was to learn that there is no immediate staffing for the clinic. Baba Jammeh, a nurse living in the village, works for the ministry in HIV and AIDS education. His work has him traveling frequently and his time in the village is limited. Further, 90% of the patients we saw needed immediate dental care. We were at a loss to provide much relief from abscessed teeth, other than temporary pain killers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucia and I came away with immediate fundraising goals for a (at least) part-time nurse to staff the clinic, a watchman to protect the solar panels, batteries and supplies, a dentist for at least once-a-month clinics. As I mentioned, Naffi has also stated that she would like to attend the University to become a registered nurse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We soon learned that we need to be patient, as things move according to &quot;Gambia Time&quot;. Lucia and I are collaborating on slide presentations, trying to raise sustainable support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot possibly thank you enough for this experience. Many of our goals were achieved. Others are going to require continued effort, but the village is now a part of us and we feel a responsibility to follow through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, peace, and endless gratitude, &lt;br&gt; Karen &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><category term="projects-2011" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ACODO (Assisting Cambodian Orphan and the Disabled Organization)</title><link href="/projects-2011/2011/08/31/project-2011-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ACODO (Assisting Cambodian Orphan and the Disabled Organization)" /><published>2011-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2011/2011/08/31/project-2011-8</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2011/2011/08/31/project-2011-8.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your August report for The $10 Club (at long last)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In December 2010, the Cambodian orphanage run by a local group in Siem Reap Province, ACODO (Assisting Cambodian Orphan and the Disabled Organization), came to The $10 Club looking for support to feed the orphans there after a flooding crisis made access to daily food provisions more complicated and expensive. Together, we stepped up to the challenge and provided sustenance to 65 children there for more than a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the rainy season in Southeast Asia has been dire this year as well, costing the region billions of dollars. The orphanage has again suffered from massive flooding and asked for our assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Siem Reap River, which flows close to the orphanage, continues to rise after these latest heavy rains. The orphanage was fortified with sandbags but flooding was unavoidable. According to Hengchhea Chheav, Founder &amp; President of ACODO, &lt;blockquote&gt;The flood this year is worse than last year. The flood waters are very deep and it will last longer. We are desperately in need of food relief for our children. Please help us do fundraising for food relief.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The water has been receding in the city very slowly and the only ways to get to the market are to walk, waist deep (or higher) in water, or pay for a big truck. The flooding has prevented the children from being able to attend school and learn English. The smaller children especially are imperiled by the high waters and drowning remains a risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Giving $10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, 250 of us joined together to donate $2,500 to ACODO to underwrite the nutrition needs of the orphans they serve. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The children served by the orphanage are desperate and need every ounce of help that can be offered. Take Mai Som, for instance. She is 9 years old, disabled (missing her leg), very sick and desperately in urgent need of bone cancer treatment. She has been transferred to an emergency room at a children's hospital in Siem Reap. The orphanage is her only stable, positive influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The orphanage serves kids who came from the streets, who lived in fear, who witnessed and were subjected to violence, and who had nowhere else to turn. There is only so much we can do. We can't cure Mai Som's cancer. We can't make the rains stop. But together we can make sure that, for another month at least, all the children there have nourishing meals to keep them going in the face of seemingly insurmountable odds.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><category term="projects-2011" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maun Homeopathy Project</title><link href="/projects-2011/2011/07/31/project-2011-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maun Homeopathy Project" /><published>2011-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2011/2011/07/31/project-2011-7</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2011/2011/07/31/project-2011-7.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your July 2011 report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since October 2005, the Maun Homeopathy Project has been running outreach clinics in and around Maun, Botswana, which has one of the highest rates of HIV and AIDS in the world. Maun treats patients who are HIV positive, who suffered after violent rapes, who witnessed attacks on family members, who are ill and raising children on their own, who have had other complicating debilitations such as strokes, and who are pregnant and need to survive and ensure the survival of their children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through previous support from The $10 Club, they were able to rent a clinic, employ a receptionist, Lebogang Sarwanyane, and expand their outreach program so that more people unable to gain access to healthcare can have the benefit of homeopathic service. The Maun Homeopathy Project has developed an outstanding reputation for helping people living with HIV and AIDS. In addition to meeting the urgent health needs of people in Botswana they also make their homeopathy service sustainable, run by and for local people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lebogang has been an incredible asset as a receptionist. According to Hilary Fairclough, the Project's Director, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;We couldn't run the clinics without her.&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;She greets clients as they arrive, makes them feel welcome and describes to them what their homeopathy treatment will involve. She has a warm and gentle manner and takes time with each client before they see the homeopath. She takes on preparations for the Outreach Clinics, maintains all client records, manages the line of clients, and takes care of all the administration and paperwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because she is inspired by homeopathy and is committed to help her community through this medicine, Lebogang has started to train to become a homeopath using the College of Practical Homeopathy's Distance Learning Course. Now she not only manages her clinic duties but studies one day a week with the financial and the teaching support of the homeopath volunteers. Said Fairclough, &quot;Lebogang is not only an essential part of the Maun Homeopathy team but is a key part of the future of homeopathy in Botswana.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The charity is able to raise money for volunteer and training expenses but has struggled to raise enough money to continue to pay Lebogang and meet their ongoing expenses for homeopathic medicines and the vehicle essential for outreach clinics and home visits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The $10 Club has been asked to donate the cost of Lebogang's salary for one year, which will enable her to continue her work and her studies and for the clinic to maximize its output, treating more than 1,000 people in desperate need of their services. This month, 250 of us joined together to donate $2,500 to the Maun Homeopathy Project to enable Lebogang Sarwanyane to complete her training as a homeopath. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sustainability is vital to the lasting impact of poverty alleviation projects. By training staff committed to the mission and the organization in this case, homeopathic treatment of HIV/AIDS patients we invest in a lifetime of homeopathic health care for Botswana's poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear 10 Dollar Club&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this letter to forward my thanks to your charity which supported me financially and to keep me going with my work and studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started joining homeopathy in 2008 as a volunteer, and I was volunteering twice a week Monday and Thursday's. I was helping with administration as well as interpreting .In 2009 Hilary Fairclough the founder and Director of Maun Homeopathy Project employed me as a receptionist and January 2011 I started to train to become a homeopath using the College of Practical Homeopathy Distance Learning Course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maun Homeopathy Project is not only in Maun, we do outreach clinics too. In villages nearby Maun and camps in the deltas we give our very good service to the people out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very happy to be employed by the Maun Homeopathy Project as a receptionist and trainee in homeopathy - it has given me a big opportunity in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours faithfully, &lt;br&gt;Kelebogile Sarwanyane&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><category term="projects-2011" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ninos con Valor</title><link href="/projects-2011/2011/06/30/project-2011-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ninos con Valor" /><published>2011-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2011/2011/06/30/project-2011-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2011/2011/06/30/project-2011-6.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your June 2011 report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bolivia is the poorest and least developed country in South America, with economic indicators that put it on par with the poorest of Sub-Saharan African nations. Children in Bolivia are especially vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August 2009 we provided Ninos con Valor with new medical instruments. Now they are raising money for the health care needs of the 36 children living in two residential homes in Cochabamba, Bolivia: Corazon del Pastor and Pedacito de Cielo. This month, 250 of us joined together to donate $2,500 for three months of healthcare, dental care, hygiene, and cleaning costs for both homes. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls and young women served by our grant this month include those who have who have been orphaned, abandoned, or removed from high-risk home situations and require specialized residential care. They are living with special needs, including HIV/AIDS, health conditions, psychiatric or psychological disorders, and/or learning disabilities and may face discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In partnership with Ninos con Valor and with our grant the Pedacito de Cielo and Corazon del Pastor centers will help break the cycle of poverty, abuse, and marginalization afflicting the resident children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together we will provide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Direct health care, including proper nutrition, medical check-ups, dental check-ups, orthodontics, specialist consultations, and prescriptions. Each child receives standard wellness check-ups through age 5, including all immunizations, and then a minimum of tri-annual medical examinations and bi-annual dental check-ups. Specialists will be seen for any chronic illness, rehabilitation needs, or any other ailment as needed. Prescriptions are purchased as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Personal hygiene for children who may arrive undernourished and dirty, with hair full of lice, skin conditions, or badly decaying teeth. Teaching proper hygiene as a normal part of the daily routine is important for maintaining a child's health, and is also a key component in building their self-esteem. The children learn to feel good about caring for themselves as they see improvements in the condition of their skin and hair.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A Sanitary Environment in which to thrive. Maintaining a high level of cleanliness and sanitation in the homes is critical for preventing many of the common childhood illnesses and contagious diseases that, for the immune-compromised children, can pose serious risks. The common cold can rapidly progress to pneumonia or bronchitis, which can result in expensive hospital stays. Our support will enable the purchasing of bulk cleaning materials for the homes, reducing costs over time, while providing the necessary supplies for a sanitary environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Ninos con Valor responds to the physical, emotional and spiritual needs of children with traumatic pasts, empowering them to reach their maximum potential and to pass on their experiences and values to other children in high-risk situations. This month, you have ensured that their vital work can continue for three more months!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Roberts</name></author><category term="projects-2011" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends,</summary></entry></feed>